when you have been in a car accident you
need someone to have your back by
purchasing a car insurance
you can make sure that someone will but
there are many types of insurance
that offer different kind of protections
which ones do you need
let's walk through the six major types
to find out
first liability liability is one type of
insurance everyone must carry it
protects
other people when you are responsible
for an accident
there are two sides of liability
coverage
bodily injury coverage and property
damage coverage
bodily injury liability insurance pays
medical bills and it can also compensate
people for things like most income and
pain
and suffering property damage liability
insurance space to repair or replace
other people vehicle that you have
damaged
it can also cover the cost of fixing
fences
and other kind of property that you may
run into
collision insurance collision insurance
protect your own vehicle
after an accident even if you are the
one at fault you will be required to buy
it
if you use a loan or lease to obtain
your vehicle
otherwise getting this protection or
your own car
is your choice number three
comprehensive insurance
comprehensive insurance protect your car
against damage
not caused by an accident such as theft
falling objects are natural disasters
it usually purchase in combination with
collision insurance
and like collision insurance you will be
required to get it
if you have a loan or lease number four
what happens if you are harmed by a
driver who doesn't have enough insurance
to cover all of your losses you are out
of luck
unless your policy include an insured
or under insured motorist coverage
depending on where you live
you may be required to get this type of
insurance
even if it's optional it's affordable
and provide important
protection fifth now let's talk about
medical bills
if you are injured in an accident they
can stack a fast
but personal injury production coverage
sometime called
no fault insurance can help with these
costs
it makes your medical bills get paid
quickly
no matter who is at fault it helps with
other expenses
like lost income child care and even
federal
number six in some states there
is a different form of insurance for
medical expenses medical
payment coverage or med pay is similar
to
personal injury protection but it's more
limited in scope unlike personal
injury protection it would pay for lost
income
or most of non-medical expenses but
it does cover accident related medical
bills for
you and your passengers supplementing
other insurance coverage